<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Monosi Documentation Blog</title>
        <link>https://docs.monosi.dev/changelog</link>
        <description>Monosi Documentation Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <copyright>Copyright © 2022 Vocable Inc. dba Monosi</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[v0.1.0 Release]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.monosi.dev/changelog/latest-release</link>
            <guid>latest-release</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Monosi v0.1.0 Release]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Monosi v0.1.0 Release</p><hr/><p>Monosi&#x27;s v0.1.0 release brings a new UI, ease of use &amp; deployment, and much more.</p><h3>Web Application &amp; UI</h3><p>In order to use the Monosi application, a web frontend and server are provided to add data sources, receive alerts, and view data quality analysis of the monitors that are running.</p><img alt="Monosi Release" class="case-study-header" src="/img/example.gif"/><h2>Automatic Scheduler</h2><p>Built-in scheduling is provided out of the box with Monosi so that you can set it and forget it - until you receive an alert - or choose to view regularly up-to-date data at any time.</p><h2>Profiler</h2><p>Built-in profiling allows for the automatic creation of data monitors and quality checks when a data source is added.</p><h3>Deployment</h3><p>Deploying has been simplified with Docker and Docker Compose. All the necessary dependencies for Monosi to run are managed through Docker Compose, making it easy to start with just 3 commands:</p><pre><code>git clone https://github.com/monosidev/monosi.git
cd monosi
make compose
</code></pre><h2>Integration Support</h2><p>Support for Snowflake, PostgreSQL, and Redshift has been added. </p><p>You can also receive alerts via webhooks and Slack.</p><h3>Documentation</h3><p>Documentation has been added to the project and is available at <a href="https://docs.monosi.dev">https://docs.monosi.dev</a></p><h3>Testing &amp; Bug fixes</h3><p>More tests have been added to ensure the reliability of the code. Furthermore, bug fixes and code changes have been made to make Monosi increasingly more stable.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>